(+91) 9119620847 Hyderabad, India hi@prashantkatiyar.com

Prashant Katiyar

Tech Entrepreneur | Product Manager

Portfolio: prashantkatiyar.com GitHub: prashantkatiyar9777 LinkedIn: prashant-milan-katiyar

Startup Founder with 3 years of experience building SaaS products in Developer Tools, Hiring, Web-3 and Retail Tech Startups, which generated over \$ 3.5 Million in revenue. I run a community of 1,20,000+ Developers, providing tools to show proof of work. I also raised \$ 150K (₹ 1.1 Cr) in Venture Capital for my startup in 2nd year of college, and got it aquihired.

EXPERIENCE

Associate Product Manager

Mar 2024 – Present Hyderabad, India

Innovapptive Inc.

- Led the 14-member Product & Engineering Team to develop the next version of the B2B SaaS offering, RACE 2.0.
- Prepared a year-long roadmap, Jira workflow initiated sprints, and three features ready to launch now.
- Played a key role in hiring Engineers to streamline processes within the new product team.
- Managed daily scrum, authored PRDs and Test Suites, prepared UI with designers, and organised Jira boards.
- Increased developers' productivity and overall sprint capacity by 80% using best practices.
- Utilized market research, customer feedback, and insights from sales to prioritize product requirements and user stories.

Founder & Head of Product May 2021 – Feb 2024

CometLabs (AcquiHired by Innovapptive Inc.)

Hyderabad, India

- Led the development of a cloud-based IDE utilizing Generative AI for code analysis and project evaluations.
- Secured INR 1.1 Cr preseed funding, served a thriving community of 120K developers & 18,000 active users.
- Built product from UI design to MVP; later supervised an 11-member engineering team.
- Established partnerships with GitHub and Vercel for seamless integrations to enhance the developer experience.
- · Adopted Agile workflows & Sprint Planning using tools like Confluence, Jira, Notion, Miro, Trello, etc.
- Outperformed competitors: 40% speedier load, 25% better efficiency, and 20% less browser memory usage within 8 months.

Associate Product Manager Dec 2020 – Sep 2021

Hapramp Studios Gurgaon, India

- Headed Creator Studio division: launching 3 major updates & initiating 4 beta tests within a 5-month timeframe.
- Drafted PRDs for Binance Wallet & KYC integration, achieving 50K+ DAU and boosting GTV.
- Conducted A/B Testing to improve performance, amplifying ASPU by 37%, Token Sales by 42% while trimming TTV by 20%.
- Coordinated closely with a 13-member Tech & Design team to ensure timely project delivery.
- Explored new revenue models by introducing NFT Minting after analyzing Web3 Market, increased revenue by 12%.

Product Intern May 2020 – Dec 2020

Moptra Infotech

Noida/Remote, India

- Collaborated with Devs to refine a supply chain tool, enhancing user satisfaction by 15%.
- Integrated Amplitude, Google Analytics & CRM with e-commerce platforms, grew engagement by 12%.
- Led design sprints, optimized JIRA product roadmaps, and crafted PRDs based on user feedback.
- Conducted A/B tests on the e-commerce platform, driving a 10% boost in user conversions.

SKILLS

Product Management Tools

Jira, Notion, Miro, Amplitude, Mixpanel, TestRail, Metabase, Google Analytics

Product Design Tools
Programming

Balsamiq, Lucid Charts, Figma, Canva, Retool SQL, C, C++, Javascript, ReactJS, Tailwind, AWS.

Core Competencies

Product Strategy, Business Analysis, User Research, Community Building, Persona Creation, Wireframing, PRD, Product Roadmap, Agile Methodology, Sprint Planning, Product Testing,

UAT, A/B Testing, Product Analytics, KPIs

EDUCATION

B. Tech. (ECE), Indian Institute of Information Technology (IIIT), Guwahati

Apr 2023

ACTIVITIES

Top 30 Finalist - HYSEA 10X Product Awards & Expo, Hyderabad
Top 5 Finalist - EO Global Student Entrepreneur Awards (GSEA), Goa & New Delhi
Founder - IIITians Network: Community of 59500+ Developers from IITs, IIITs

20232023

2021 - 2022